<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>Connected Objects</title>
<link>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/</link>
<atom:link href="https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<image>
<url>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/assets/art_title_path_only.svg</url>
<title>Connected Objects</title>
<link>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/</link>
</image>
<generator>quarto-1.4.553</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>Grading Update</title>
  <link>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-04-22-grades-update.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Hello everyone,</p>
<p>Your grades for L4, L5, Q1, and Milestone 1 have been updated. You can find your feedback on Moodle in most cases.</p>
<p>For the milestone, your detailed feedback has been included in the “Teacher Feedback” issue of your repository.</p>
<p><strong>Note for April 22 morning section</strong>: I will be around 15-20 minutes late. Please get your Lab 6 demos ready while you are waiting.</p>



<a onclick="window.scrollTo(0, 0); return false;" id="quarto-back-to-top"><i class="bi bi-arrow-up"></i> Back to top</a> ]]></description>
  <guid>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-04-22-grades-update.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Azure Plan Troubleshooting</title>
  <link>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-04-18-azure-plan-troubleshooting.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>In setting up Azure for Lab 6, a few students have asked me about troubles with the following:</p>
<ul>
<li>Eligibility for a student Azure plan</li>
<li>Student Azure plan expiring</li>
<li>Signing up for the Free-tier of Azure</li>
<li>Creating a budget for Azure</li>
<li>Difficulties creating an Azure IoTHub on the Free-tier plan</li>
<li>Etc.</li>
</ul>
<p>I would like to share my help for those students for the rest of you, just in case there are more of you struggling with setting up Azure.</p>
<p>I will keep the Course Website version of this announcement up to date – if you are seeing this announcement on Moodle, you can <a href="https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-04-18-azure-plan-troubleshooting.html">click here</a> to get to the up-to-date version of this announcement with the latest change</p>
<section id="big-picture" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="big-picture">Big picture</h2>
<p>In the big picture, no matter what your situation is, your Azure plan should have the following properties:</p>
<ol type="1">
<li><p>No <strong>upfront</strong> costs – your account should be free to create, and every service/resource you create should be free to create.</p></li>
<li><p>No <strong>monthly</strong> costs – your costs should be covered entirely by one of the following:</p></li>
</ol>
<ul>
<li><ol type="a">
<li>your student account credit</li>
</ol></li>
<li><ol start="2" type="a">
<li>$200 free credit for new non-student account</li>
</ol></li>
<li><ol start="3" type="a">
<li>pay-as-you-go that is <strong>free per month</strong>, but will charge your credit card <strong>per usage</strong>.</li>
</ol></li>
</ul>
<ol start="3" type="1">
<li>A budget alert system that warns you when your usage exceeds &gt;$5 . Even if you are in situation (c), you should not expect to pay more than $5 or $10 – <strong>please set up an alert system and monitor this. Let me know if your costs ever exceed this amount</strong>. See the <a href="../topics/iot/docs/what-is-iot.html#azure-account-check">course notes on Azure Account Check</a>.</li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="faq" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="faq">FAQ</h2>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Q: I’m not eligible for a student account?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Student accounts last for 18 months – if you have taken courses in the past that require an Azure account, and it was more than 18 months since you created that account, your student credits have unfortunately expired. There are other free options in this case.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Q: I’m not eligible for the $200 free account credit for my non-student account?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The $200 credit is only available if you have not used that email address for an Azure account in the past (and it only lasts for one month).</p>
<p>If you are not elgible for the $200 credit on the email address you have provided, you have two choices, both of which are fine:</p>
<ul>
<li>use a new email address</li>
<li>register for a free-tier pay-as-you-go.</li>
</ul>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Q: I tried to register for the pay-as-you-go and I’m told it costs $35 per month?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The pay-as-you-go account <strong>should not cost any upfront or monthly charges</strong>. Double check that you do not select options like “tech support plans” or “standard-tier service” – ALWAYS opt out of any paid options, ALWAYS select free-tier for any choices provided to you by Azure.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Q: if I’m on free-tier and there’s no monthly costs, why do I need to monitor the budget?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The pay-as-you-go account may charge your credit card, only when you <em>use</em> the service <em>beyond the defined free-tier limits</em>.</p>
<p>In our class, we will have IoT Hub services that handle communication between your Mobile App from App Dev III, and your reTerminal devices from Connected Objects. <strong>The free-tier limit for the IoTHub is 8000 messages per day</strong> – I don’t think there will be a reason to exceed this, so by default, you may never have to pay any money for this serivce.</p>
<p>However, there may be small charges to your credit card, ONLY IF you exceed the free-tier limits of the services we use. These charges will be small, but it is possible for them to get out-of-hand by accident. To make sure they do not get out of hand by accident, you must set up a Budget for your Resource Group to alert you when charges exceed a certain number. <a href="../topics/iot/docs/what-is-iot.html#azure-account-check">Please review the course notes about budgets and set up an alert if you have not done so</a>.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Q: I have some other question?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Please let me know if you have any questions, or if there’s something else that doesn’t seem to work. I will update these instructions if there are more troubles you run into that I can share answers for. Again, if you are seeing this on moodle, <a href="https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-04-18-azure-plan-troubleshooting.html">click here</a> to see the latest version of these instructions.</p>


</section>

<a onclick="window.scrollTo(0, 0); return false;" id="quarto-back-to-top"><i class="bi bi-arrow-up"></i> Back to top</a> ]]></description>
  <guid>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-04-18-azure-plan-troubleshooting.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 18 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Mid-April Schedule Updates</title>
  <link>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-04-15-schedule-updates.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>I’ve made a series of updates to the course website and Moodle, some of which are worth emphasizing because I think they’ll be particularly useful to you:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="../about/calendar.html">Course Calendar</a>: I’ve updated the <strong>April</strong> section of the calendar with the latest set of deliverables.</li>
<li><strong>Final Project Description and Milestones</strong>: I’ve uploaded all remaining Connected Objects Milestones onto Moodle. Links for <a href="https://moodle.johnabbott.qc.ca/course/view.php?id=807&amp;section=2">Section 1</a>, <a href="https://moodle.johnabbott.qc.ca/course/view.php?id=808&amp;section=2">Section 2</a></li>
<li><a href="../topics/index.html">Lectures</a>: There are a new set of IoT lectures which should help you with Lab 6 (links for <a href="https://moodle.johnabbott.qc.ca/mod/assign/view.php?id=32610">Section 1</a>, <a href="https://moodle.johnabbott.qc.ca/mod/assign/view.php?id=32633">Section 2</a>). We will also cover this ground on Assignment 2 (TBA) and future project milestones. This is the (almost) the final set of lectures for this class, and will be covered in Quiz 2.</li>
</ul>
<p>Let me know if you have any questions, or if there’s something that doesn’t seem to work.</p>



<a onclick="window.scrollTo(0, 0); return false;" id="quarto-back-to-top"><i class="bi bi-arrow-up"></i> Back to top</a> ]]></description>
  <guid>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-04-15-schedule-updates.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Quiz 1: Topics/Information</title>
  <link>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-03-18-quiz1-topics.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><strong>Quiz 1</strong> will take place in-class on <strong>Friday, March 22.</strong>. This announcement contains logistical and topics covered.</p>
<section id="logistics" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="logistics">Logistics</h2>
<ul>
<li>worth 2%</li>
<li>Multiple choice / short-answer on Moodle, in-class. 15-30 minutes.</li>
<li>Limited open-book: access to course notes, reTerminal, workstation, but not external resources.</li>
</ul>
</section>
<section id="topics" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="topics">Topics</h2>
<p>There will be 5-10 short-answer questions covering concepts that we have seen in Labs 0-3 of this course. Broadly, that is the following topics:</p>
<ul>
<li>Linux: using <code>apt</code>, <code>apt</code> for python packages, frequently used Bash concepts/commands like <code>tar</code>, shebangs, workflow for reading/writing to reTerminal interfaces. Anything covered in the labs explicitly.</li>
<li>Python: installing local packages using <code>venv</code> and <code>pip</code>, workflow for reading/writing to reTerminal interfaces, libraries vs scripts</li>
<li>Hardware: reTerminal sensors, GPIO, Analog vs Digital signals</li>
</ul>
<p>To help with reviewing, I have added all of the relevant lectures to the <strong>Quiz 1</strong> category on this course website. <strong>Click on the <a href="../topics/index.html">Lectures</a> tab of the course website and click “Quiz 1” to filter the relevant lectures.</strong></p>
<p>Let me know if you have any questions!</p>


</section>

<a onclick="window.scrollTo(0, 0); return false;" id="quarto-back-to-top"><i class="bi bi-arrow-up"></i> Back to top</a> ]]></description>
  <guid>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-03-18-quiz1-topics.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 18 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>On updating your pi</title>
  <link>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-03-14-pi-update.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>A few students have run into system updates that may break important reTerminal features (the screen, for e.g.). If you run into any issues when updating your pi software, see below!</p>
<p>The standard Debian commands for updating system software:</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb1" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode bash code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode bash"><span id="cb1-1"><span class="ex" style="color: null;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">$</span> sudo apt update <span class="kw" style="color: #003B4F;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">&amp;&amp;</span> <span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">sudo</span> apt upgrade <span class="at" style="color: #657422;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">-y</span></span></code></pre></div>
<p>The latest linux updates have <a href="https://forum.seeedstudio.com/t/running-seeed-linux-dtoverlays-in-reterminal-fails-to-build-device-driver/275675">introduced some significant changes to i2c interface</a> which may cause your pi LCD screen, among other hardware, to fail.</p>
<p>For now, when updating your pi software, you should also do the following:</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb2" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode bash code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode bash"><span id="cb2-1"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;"># If this folder does not exist, run the following command first:</span></span>
<span id="cb2-2"><span class="co" style="color: #5E5E5E;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;"># cd ~/ &amp;&amp; git clone https://github.com/Seeed-Studio/seeed-linux-dtoverlays</span></span>
<span id="cb2-3"><span class="bu" style="color: null;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">cd</span> ~/seeed-linux-dtoverlays </span>
<span id="cb2-4"><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">git</span> pull</span></code></pre></div>
<p>If there are any updates when the <code>git pull</code> is run, you should re-run the setup script:</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb3" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode bash code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode bash"><span id="cb3-1"><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">sudo</span> ./scripts/reTerminal.sh</span></code></pre></div>
<p>Then, finally, reboot the device:</p>
<div class="sourceCode" id="cb4" style="background: #f1f3f5;"><pre class="sourceCode bash code-with-copy"><code class="sourceCode bash"><span id="cb4-1"><span class="fu" style="color: #4758AB;
background-color: null;
font-style: inherit;">sudo</span> reboot</span></code></pre></div>



<a onclick="window.scrollTo(0, 0); return false;" id="quarto-back-to-top"><i class="bi bi-arrow-up"></i> Back to top</a> ]]></description>
  <guid>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-03-14-pi-update.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Website updates</title>
  <link>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-03-12-website-updates.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>I’ve made a few changes to the course website, some of which are worth emphasizing because I think they’ll be particularly useful to you:</p>
<ul>
<li><a href="../about/calendar.html">Course Calendar</a>: The defunct Calendar page is now being maintained. Check this page for upcoming lecture/lab activity, particularly for Lab demo deadlines. I will keep it maintained throughout the rest of the semester.</li>
<li><a href="../announcements/">Announcements</a>: Announcements like this one will be posted on the course website and (sort-of) automatically posted on Moodle as well. If you like <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RSS">RSS</a>, you can subcribe using the <iconify-icon inline="" icon="simple-icons:moodle" aria-label="Icon moodle from simple-icons Iconify.design set." title="Icon moodle from simple-icons Iconify.design set."></iconify-icon> icon in the nav bar.</li>
<li><a href="../topics/">Lecture index</a>: I’ve fixed some metadata and theming issues for the <a href="../topics/">Topics</a> page (also called Lectures). Here you can find an index of every course lecture, and sort them by category. This should help keep track of topics and things learned.</li>
</ul>
<p>Let me know if you have any questions, or if there’s something that doesn’t seem to work.</p>



<a onclick="window.scrollTo(0, 0); return false;" id="quarto-back-to-top"><i class="bi bi-arrow-up"></i> Back to top</a> ]]></description>
  <guid>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-03-12-website-updates.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Lab 3: Demo in class Friday March 15</title>
  <link>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-03-12-lab3-demo.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>As mentioned in class on March 11, the hand-in for <strong>Lab 3</strong> will be on <strong>Friday March 15</strong>. Demos will start at the <strong>beginning</strong> of class. Come to class prepared to show your progress.</p>
<p>The deadline to submit your scripts for Lab 3 code remains midnight on Friday.</p>
<p>If you have not completed the lab by Friday morning, you will get partial marks up to whatever you have completed.</p>
<p>Let me know if you have any questions! (by Teams preferably)</p>



<a onclick="window.scrollTo(0, 0); return false;" id="quarto-back-to-top"><i class="bi bi-arrow-up"></i> Back to top</a> ]]></description>
  <guid>https://john-abbott-college.github.io/6P3-Notes/announcements/2024-03-12-lab3-demo.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
